Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin slavery collection, 1728-1973.
Rudin (Gail and Stephen) Slavery Collection,
- Series XIII: Pamphlets and Printed Documents
  - Statement of the Sugar Crop in Louisiana, 1860; Location: New Orleans, LA Format: Booklet (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 540
  - Anti-Slavery tracts, No. 15 - "The Fugitive Slave Law and its Victims", 1861; Location: Anti-Slaver Society, New York Format: Book (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 890
  - Third Volume of "Vanity Fair" Magazine with Historical Black Theme Illustrations, June 15, 1861; Location: New York Format: Magazine (Box 17, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 429
  - Jefferson Davis's First Message to Congress: announcing the ratification of the constitution of the Confederate States, April 29, 1861; Location: Montgomery, Alabama Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 990
  - Congressional Resolution: The Case of the Slave Vessel Bark Augusta, 1862; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 606B
  - "The Slave Power", 1862; Location: T.J. Crowen, Publisher New York Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 213
  - Slavery Abolished in Washington DC - Speech of Hon. E.H. Rollins, April 11, 1862; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 557
  - Civil War Circular dealing with freed blacks who remained on plantations to work, July 3, 1862; Location: Beaufort, South Carolina Format: Ptd Docs (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 311
  - Lincoln's Bill to Compensate States for Abolishing Slavery, July 14, 1862; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 473
  - Before the Emancipation Proclamation, Lincoln Approves Congressional Bill That Frees Slaves - The Second Confiscation Act, July 17, 1862; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 477
  - Confederate Imprints (5), 1863 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 44
  - "Public Laws of the State of North Carolina", 1863; Location: Raleigh, North Carolina Format: BOOK (Box 9, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 536
  - Confederate Report on Treatment of Slaves Working on the Fortifications Around Richmond, 1863; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: Ptd DOC (Box 9, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 290
  - Reports of suffering from the late riots in New York City, 1863; Location: New York Format: Booklet (Box 9, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 640
  - Slavers capture - the slaves transferred to Liberia, January 7, 1863; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 812
  - "A Thrilling Narrative from the Lips of the Sufferers of the Late Detroit Riot", March 6, 1863; Location: Detroit, Michigan Format: Pamphlet (Box 9, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 1025
  - Call to Arms to Colored Men to Join the Union Army plus A Plea to Private Citizens for Money to Help the State Meet its Overall Recruiting of Colored Troops, June 27, 1863; Location: 1210 Chestnut Street Philadelphia Format: Ptd DOC (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 444
  - "The Gospel of Slavery: A Primer of Freedom". Juvenile with 26 Engravings Accompanied by Anti-Slavery Verses, 1864; Location: T.W. Strong New York Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 486
  - "The First Dixie Reader to Succeed the Dixie Primer", 1864; Location: Raleigh, North Carolina Format: Booklet (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 717
  - Document Used to Appoint an Agent to Draft Slaves into the Confederate Military, 1864; Location: Office of Chief Agent of Impressment Mobile, Alabama Format: Ptd DOC (Box 17, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 483
  - Slave Compensation Imprint Pertaining to the Cost of Slave Labor to the Confederacy, February 1, 1864; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: Ptd DOC (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 559
  - Listing of over 900 slaves bought by the Government, then given emancipation under District of Columbia Compensated Emancipation Act, February 17, 1864; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Booklet (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 836
  - US Senate Bill 188 to Prohibit Commerce in Slaves, March 22, 1864; Format: Ptd ACT (Box 17, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 227
  - Jefferson Davis acknowledges the federal government’s passage of the 13th Amendment, February 6, 1865; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 891
  - Confederate Imprint Authorizing Jefferson Davis to Organize Negro Troops for the Confederate Army, February 10, 1865; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 324
  - The Freed Slaves are Allowed to Vote - Statement of the number of white and colored voters registered in each of the states subject to the Reconstruction Acts of Congress, December 5, 1867; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 572
  - Congressional imprint- reports on the Opelousas, Louisiana massacre of 1868, December 14, 1868; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: Ptd Doc (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 964
  - "The Registration of Voters Under the Act of Congress to Enforce the Fifteenth Amendment", 1870; Location: Parkersburg, West Virginia Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 984
  - "The Jim Mace Reciter or the Gem of Oratory" - black dialect pulp book, 1870; Location: New York Format: Book (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 863
  - "Cotton Movement and Fluctuations 1869 to 1877", 1877; Location: New York Format: Book (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 537
  - Broadsheet handbill with engraving of Blind Boone, selected concert selections, and biographical information, 1880; Location: Bloomington, Illinois Format: Ptd Handbill (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 773
  - Diecut book - "Ten Little Niggers", 1897; Location: New York Format: Book (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 742
  - "The Literary Movement for Secession", 1914; Location: New York Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 872
  - The Amenia Conference, and Historic Negro Gathering - WEB Dubois, 1925; Location: Amenia, New York Format: Booklet (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 903
- Series XIV: Patriotic Covers
  - Patriotic Cover album, containing 200 unused covers, Format: Album (Box 35)
    Rudin # S - 854
  - Collection of over 100 unused patriotic covers, Format: Album (Box 36)
    Rudin # S - 893
  - "Secession Cavalry" (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 230
  - Lot of Six Union Slavery-related Covers, Format: (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 282
  - Five Union covers (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 373
  - Patriotic Cover - Depicts President Davis in Refrigerator with Slave Standing Along Side (Box 10, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 482
  - Patriotic Cover - Contrabands Dancing, Location: Murphy's Son, Printer New York (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 510
  - Envelope printed with Emancipation Proclamation (Box 13, Folder 36a)
    Rudin # S - 514
  - 36 Union postal covers (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 645
  - Five covers using contraband images (Box 10, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 702
  - "Contraband Barricade", "Jeff's Unbounded Ambition", "One of the Ends of Secession" (Box 10, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 727
  - "The Southern Army as it Enters Washington", "The Downfall of Secession Treason!" (Box 10, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 728
  - Five Confederate Covers (Box 10, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 733
  - Four Union Covers (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 735
  - "The Snake of Secession" (Box 10, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 739
  - "Music by the Contra-Band" - 2 copies, one with black ink and one with blue (Box 10, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 764, 765
  - Three covers (Box 10, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 794
  - Five slavery themed covers (Box 10, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 809
  - Ten patriotic covers (Box 10, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 884-886
  - Serpent "Secession" wrapped around a nude Columbia (Box 10, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 892
  - "The Union Forever" (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 898
  - Cover showing the devil prodding and roasting Jefferson Davis over a grill (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 907
  - Cover to promote abolitionist cause (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 908
  - Eleven covers satirizing Davis and celebrating the waning days of slavery (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 909
  - Cover of Jefferson Davis hanging on a gallows "Long may HE wave" (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 911
  - "Virginia Begins the War" (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 914
  - "Free Speech at the South" (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 915
  - "Blood Money: Or How Southern Rebels Encourage Piracy" (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 916
  - "Bringing Down Secession" (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 918
  - Five contrabands approach federal General Butler (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 969
  - Cover displaying two renderings when card is turned (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 970
  - Two music-themed patriotic covers (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 1008
  - Five covers (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 1021
  - British anti-slavery cover "God Hath Made of One Blood All Nations of Men", ca. 1834 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 995
  - Devil seated on cotton bales with 18 line verse ensign with "Cotton is King", 1861 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 738
  - Caricature of an eagle battling the southern snake, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 740
  - A wet-nurse anti-slavery union cover, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 808
  - Slave Pen - Multicolor Magnus, ca. 1861; Location: Alexandria, VA (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 313
  - 21 Union patriotic covers, 1861-1865 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 122
  - Two Patriotic Covers, 1861-1865 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 169
  - Patriotic Cover, 1861-1865 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 174
  - Ten covers, ca. 1862-1865 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 642
  - Confederate cover of a snake broken into 15 segments representing the states of the confederacy, captioned "Unite or Die", ca. 1863 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 933
  - Contrabands of war, ca. 1863 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 934
  - Contraband Envelope, ca. 1863 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 85
  - Twenty-four patriotic covers, all postmarked Virginia, April 9, 1865 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 744
- Series XV: Runaway Slave Documents
  - Capturing Runaways in Florida - An Account of Expenses, Location: Florida Format: MDOC (Box 11, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 340
  - Three slaves kill sheep and hog and run away. They must be caught and treated with "severity"., January 30, 1797; Location: White House Format: ALS (Box 11, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 254
  - Document concerning runaway slave, signed Isaac Ford, December 22, 1804; Location: Baltimore, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 79
  - Letter about slave girl who ran away, October 14, 1807; Location: New York Format: ALS (Box 40, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 343
  - Document Pertaining to a Runaway Slave who was Committed to Jail - With Attached Newspaper Clipping, April 18, 1808; Location: Columbia, South Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 465
  - Runaway Slave is Sent Home, May 1, 1823; Location: Philadelphia Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 253
  - Underground Railroad Related Document - Fine is Levied for Harbouring Runaway Slave, February 7, 1827; Location: Richmond County, Georgia Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 17, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 331
  - Newspaper Charge for Advertising Runaway Slave Held in Jail, August 18, 1837; Location: Dahlonega, Georgia Format: MDocS (Box 11, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 416
  - Slave Woman, Jenny Had Run Off - Asking if She Could be Caught and Returned, June 22, 1838; Location: Raleigh Format: ALS (Box 17, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 458
  - Runaway slave broadside for woman named Jane, c. 1820-1840; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: Broadside (Box 11, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 925
  - Runaway Slave Stowaway on Ship, April 27, 1842; Location: Ponce (Puerto Rico) Format: ALS (Box 11, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 285
  - Attempt to capture escaped slave, 1850; Location: South Carolina Format: ALS (Box 11, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 65
  - Runaway Slave Broadside, 1853; Location: Virginia Format: Broadside (Box 17, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 175
  - Writ for Runaway Slave, 1854; Location: Maryland (Box 11, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 111
  - Runaway Slave Broadside for Henry Carroll, May 22, 1854; Location: Maryland (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 821
  - Reward Notice for Runaway Slave, 1855; Location: Missouri (Box 11, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 26
  - Invoice for Capture of Runaway Slave, 1856; Location: Mississippi Format: (Box 11, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 106
  - Bounty for Capturing Runaway Slave, February 5, 1857; Location: Dinwiddie County, Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 11, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 496
  - Underground Railroad Letter, 1858 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 33
  - Indictment for harboring runaway slaves, 1860; Location: Tennessee (Box 17, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 32
  - Letter Regarding Runaway Slave, July 28, 1861; Location: West Virginia Format: ALS (Box 11, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 113
  - Harboring Runaway Slaves, September 16, 1862; Location: Lumpkin County, Georgia Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 386
  - Writes of Slaves Who Fled From Their Masters, November 16, 1862; Location: Steam Boat "Tecumseh" Format: ALS (Box 11, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 379
  - Union Soldier letter in which master kills a slave from Ft. Pillow, Tennessee, February 24, 1863; Format: ALS (Box 11, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 82
  - Writes That Four Slaves Have Run Away. (With Multi Color Floral Wallpaper Envelope), January 11, 1864; Format: ALS (Box 11, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 378
  - Ohio Land Grant for a Runaway or Freed Slave, 1891, September 10, 1844; Location: Lucas County, Ohio Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 41, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 589
- Series XVI: Sale, Hire, Purchase, Collateral Documents
  - Broadside - Gang of Thirty-Seven Negroes For Sale (In Families), Location: Florida Format: Ptd Broadside (Box 17, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 402
  - Receipt for the sale of Native American man named Jack, signed Edmund Toppan and Edward Shaw, September 20, 1731; Location: Hampton, New Hampshire Format: MDocS (Box 11, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 618
  - New York Bill of Sale for a "Negro man, Cuffee" the British embossed revenue tax stamp, September 27, 1758; Location: New York Format: Ptd Doc (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 978
  - Slave Bill of Sale, April 15, 1764; Location: Hartford Co., Conn/Schenectady, New York (Box 17, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 120
  - Selling Rum and Slaves in Colonial New York, October 7, 1768; Location: Newport, Rhode Island Format: Alabama (Box 17, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 200
  - Bill of Sale for two children, 1776; Location: Maryland (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 19
  - Slaves given as gifts to daughter and family, November 15, 1777; Location: Washington County, Pennsylvania Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 403
  - Bill of Sale for a Fugitive Slave who has run to Boston. Payment will only be made if the slave can be obtained., February 21, 1785; Location: Enfield Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 548
  - Letter from John Chestnut, loaning slave to a poor woman, 1792; Location: South Carolina (Box 17, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 117
  - Sale of Man Named Davy for 70 Pounds, April 29, 1794 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Deed of Gift of a Slave, January 15, 1796; Location: North Carolina (Box 17, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 116
  - Sale of Girl Called Sali, 18 Years Old, November 14, 1796 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Thomas Clifford becomes a Five Year Apprentice to John Winter, a Wheelwright, April 14, 1798 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Georgia Bill of Sale for Slave Simon, May 7, 1803; Location: Wilkes County, Georgia Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 436
  - Court Agreement to Make a Free Negro Child an Apprentice Until She Reaches the Age of Eighteen, October 12, 1804; Location: South Eastern District of Campbell County Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 430
  - Slave Woman, Lydia, for 3.2 Pounds, 10 Shillings - 6 Year Term and She Can Go Free. Also, Boy Tom (9 Months) To Go Free after 29 Years, 3 Months, November 7, 1805 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Two bills of sale for slaves, plus notes and photographs, 1806-1925; Location: Various Format: Various (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Sale of Man Named Harry, 1806 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Receipt of Captured Negroes, 1812; Location: Sierra Leone (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 4
  - Slave Girl Given as Present Until She is 28 Years Old, August 24, 1812; Location: Geneseo Format: ALS (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 327
  - New York Slave Bill of Sale, 1812 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 51
  - Slave Bill of Sale signed by Henry Clay, 1813 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 56
  - North Carolina Illegal Slave Sale Document - Free Born Child of Color Offered for Sale as a Slave, March 2, 1813; Location: County of Rowan Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 466
  - Free Negro Boy is Indentured by the Overseers of the Poor, December 31, 1815; Location: County of Campbell Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 555
  - Fees charged for selling three slaves, signed by Thomas Helm, 1821; Location: Lincoln County, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 628
  - Sale of five Negroes, Animals, House, Crops and Timber, all in One Lot, May 8, 1821; Location: Bertie County, North Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 299
  - Sale-One Negro Man, Jerry, 21 Years Old to pay a debt of $200, December 29, 1821 (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Indenture, using two slave children as collateral for a debt, December 31, 1821 (Box 40, Folder 29a)
    Rudin # S - 644
  - Slave Family Sold at Auction, January 3, 1823; Location: Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 252
  - Seizure of Three Slaves, One Wagon, Four Steers, One Horse to Satisfy a Debt, November 24, 1823; Location: Alabama Format: Ptd DOC (Box 17, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 478
  - Carolyn Shupp sells "One Black Man", a bed and other property to Elias Greshow, September 13, 1824; Location: Frederick County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 858B
  - Slave Hire Journal, William Turner, 1825-1840; Format: Manu- Journal (Box 12, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 322
  - Indenture - $1000 Buys One Brick House and Lot of Ground Plus One frame House and Lot of Ground in Annapolis, 1826 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - An account of hire of men, farm and house of James Lakenan made by William Gardner, January 22, 1827; Location: St. Louis, Mississippi Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 858A
  - Man Buys Slave Relative - Possibly His Son, September 8, 1829; Location: City of Washington Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 43)
    Rudin # S - 412
  - Governor of Georgia Buys a Slave, February 15, 1830; Location: Georgia Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 40, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 338
  - Rody, a free woman of color, buys her own daughter, a mulatto child, from James Whiteside, for the sum of two hundred dollars., October 18, 1830; Location: Georgia Format: DOCS (Box 40, Folder 31a)
    Rudin # S - 670
  - Indentured Servant Agreement, August 3, 1831; Location: Pickaway County, Ohio Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 44)
    Rudin # S - 388
  - Document of Slave purchased and freed by mother, October 18, 1831; Location: Maryland (Box 12, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 59
  - Detailing the Sale of 17 Slaves by Two Free People of Color, 1833; Location: Iberville Parish, Louisiana Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 45)
    Rudin # S - 395
  - Receipt for Money Paid to Advertise the Sale of a Slave, February 6, 1833; Location: Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 279
  - Bill of Sale for twelve year-old boy, July 12, 1833; Location: Washington, DC (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 25
  - Rebecca Jones Sells a Slave Named Tom to Riley C. Jones, November 18, 1835; Location: North Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Potential Buyer for a Slave Bricklayer, November 11, 1836; Location: Louisville, Mississippi Format: ALS (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 240
  - Conveyance of two slaves to pay a debt, December 5, 1837; Location: North Carolina (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 11
  - Debt levied on slaves and horses, 1838; Location: Tennessee Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 47)
    Rudin # S - 150
  - Two children to be sold to cover a debt, June 23, 1838; Location: Tennessee Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 48)
    Rudin # S - 112
  - Letter Requesting Payment to a Slave for Amount Due for Hauling, March 8, 1839; Location: Love Spring, Tennessee Format: ALS (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 417
  - Legal Document pertaining to the sale and transfer of slaves, February 10, 1840; Location: North Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 49)
    Rudin # S - 46
  - Manuscript Document, regarding Slave for hire, January 1841; Location: Virginia (Box 12, Folder \18)
    Rudin # S - 7
  - Certificate of Title, April 6, 1841; 1843; Location: Louisiana (Box 12, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 147
  - Preacher attempts to buy the wife of one of his slaves, December 8, 1841; Location: Natchez, Mississippi Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 767
  - Power of Attorney to sell slave, June 30, 1842; Location: Louisiana (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 102
  - Natchez Courier Journal - Slave Auction Advertisement - Proof of Publication, December 29, 1842; Location: Natchez, Mississippi Format: Ptd DOC (Box 40, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 250
  - Slave Hire, January 2, 1843; Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 330
  - Slave Bill of Sale for "mulatto" woman and two children, February 7, 1843; Location: Louisiana (Box 17, Folder 50)
    Rudin # S - 34
  - Letter giving notice of a sale of slaves at auction, one of whom wishes to be purchased by the addressee, who owns his wife., September 16, 1843; Location: Middlesex County, Virginia Format: ALS (Box 12, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 289
  - Female Slave Hire, 1844; Location: Petersburg, Virginia Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 12, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 258
  - Bill of Sale for a Slave Family, May 18, 1844; Location: New Orleans Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 502
  - Free man buys slave, April 4, 1845; Location: Louisiana Format: MDocS (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 188
  - "Negroes Wanted - The Cash is Deposited for the Purchase of a Few Likely Young Negros From 12 to 25 Years of Age - Enquire at the Sheriff's Office", 1844-1845; Location: Sumterville, SC Format: Printed Doc (Box 41, Folder 5a)
    Rudin # S - 876
  - Slave Owner Seeks to Sell One of his Child Slaves, May 22, 1845; Location: Henrico County, Virginia Format: ALS (Box 12, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 337
  - Slave buys his own freedom, October 31, 1845; Location: Washington, DC Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 51)
    Rudin # S - 2
  - Payment for a Slave Working on a Chain Gang, December 5, 1845; Location: New Orleans Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 12, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 520
  - Supreme court case revolving around the sale of a sick slave, ca. 1846; Location: Baton Rouge, Louisiana Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 12, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 987
  - Bill of Sale for two four year- old children, March 2, 1846; Location: Georgia (Box 12, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 67
  - Slave Receipt, April 10, 1846; Location: Virginia (Box 12, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 10
  - Inherited slave to be sold by heirs, April 16, 1846; Location: Alabama (Box 17, Folder 52)
    Rudin # S - 38
  - Slaves for Collateral for a Debt, April 24, 1846; Location: Washington, DC (Box 17, Folder 53)
    Rudin # S - 24
  - Bill of Sale for a woman, March 19, 1847 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 20